{
    "questions" : [
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "47_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Man : Welcome. How can I help you.\nWoman : I'm here to submit the application documents for new employees.\nMan: You can go to the 3rd floor. Use the elevator over there",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "47_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Man : What do you want to drink? Coffee ? \nWoman : Yes. I want to have a cup of warm coffee.\nMan: Then go first and sit down. I'll take it",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "47_3_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "②  ",
            "detail"        : "Man : The consumer base of the publishing market is changing. According to the book purchase rate by age over the past 10 years, the purchase rate in the 20s, which accounted for the largest proportion, decreased and increased in the 40s. By field, 'literature' was the most common, followed by 'self-development' and 'induring'.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "4. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  점심시간이 몇 시예요?",
            "option_2"      : "②  점심 맛있게 드셨어요?",
            "option_3"      : "③  빨리 정리하고 나가죠.",
            "option_4"      : "④  지금은 배가 안 고픈데요.",
            "detail"        : "Man : It's lunch time, so let's go eat.\nWoman : Is the time already like that? By the way, I'm hungry.\nMan : Let's clean up quickly and go out.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  빨리 정리하고 나가죠.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "5. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  농구 경기 보러 꼭 오면 좋겠어요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  잘할 수 있을 테니까 걱정하지 마세요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  바빠서 연습 경기에 많이 못 갔거든요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  체육 대회가 끝나고 나니까 피곤하네요.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Minsu, I heard you're going out as a basketball player in this athletic competition?\nMan : Yes. But I don't know if I can do well because I can't practice much.\nWoman : You'll do well, so don't worry.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  잘할 수 있을 테니까 걱정하지 마세요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "6. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  네.일할 곳을 찾고 있어요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  네.제가 대신 해 드릴게요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  네.좀 알아봐 주면 좋겠어요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  네.그 친구는 아르바이트해요.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Jiyoung, do you have any friends who can work part-time?\nWoman : Well. I'm not sure, but should I ask my friends?\nMan : Yes. I'd like you to look into it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  네.좀 알아봐 주면 좋겠어요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "7. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  그래요?그럼 창문을 닫아야겠네요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  정말요?그럼 에어컨 좀 켜 주세요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  맞아요.많이 덥지 않아서 다행이에요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  글쎄요.아마 사무실은 열려 있을 거예요.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Don't you think the office is very hot right now? Do you want me to turn on the air conditioner.\nMan : I turned on the air conditioner. I guess it's because I left the window open a while ago to ventilate.\nWoman : Is that so? Then I have to close the window.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  그래요?그럼 창문을 닫아야겠네요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "8. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  참석자 명단은 아까 드렸는데요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  회의에 참석해 주셔서 감사해요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이쪽 자리로 와서 앉으시면 돼요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  그럼 확실히 정해지면 알려 주세요.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Mr. Kim, could you give me a list of attendees for this meeting? I have to make a placement table.\nMan : Oh, yes. But I'm not sure about the number of attendees yet.\nWoman : Then let me know when it's decided for sure.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  그럼 확실히 정해지면 알려 주세요.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "9. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  사무실에 전화한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  컴퓨터를 확인한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  장학금을 신청한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  학교 홈페이지를 본다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : The computer doesn't work. I have to apply for a scholarship by today. \nMan : What? Did you apply for the scholarship until today? Is it correct.\nWoman : I saw it like that on the school homepage. Do you want me to call the office?\nMan : Yes, try it. I'll check the computer.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  사무실에 전화한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "10. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  집에 간다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  상품을 정리한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  자료를 만든다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  두통약을 사러 간다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I'll go to the pharmacy for a while. I need to take some medicine for my headache. \nMan : If you're not feeling well, go home quickly and take a rest. I'll organize the rest of the exhibition products.\nWoman : No. I haven't even made the explanatory materials yet.\nMan : Yes, then go. I'll be organizing this",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  두통약을 사러 간다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "11. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  자전거를 꺼낸다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  옷을 갈아입는다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  공원에서 운동한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  동생과 같이 나간다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Jun-gi, where did you put your battery?\nMan : It's on the veranda....... Sister, are you going to ride a ride a ride? Do you want me to take it out.\nWoman : No. I'll take it out Don't you want to go out with me? The weather is nice, so let's work out together in the park.\nMan : Yes. Then I'll change my clothes and come out.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  자전거를 꺼낸다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "12. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  카드로 계산한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  안내 센터에 간다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  배달 신청을 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  집에서 물건을 받는다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Customer, it's all 120,000 won.\nWoman : Please pay with this card here. By the way, do you also deliver it to your home?\nMan : of course Here is the receipt You can go to the information center with this and apply.\nWoman : Oh, yes. Thank you for By the way, when can I get the item?\nMan : It usually takes about two or three hours.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  안내 센터에 간다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "13. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자는 현재 구청에서 일하고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  남자는 프로그램에 대해 알아볼 것이다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 이 프로그램에 참여한 적이 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자는 이 프로그램에 대해 들은 적이 없다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : The ward office is running a career counseling program.\nMan : yeah. I heard it too I heard that they will also do an aptitude test for free.\nWoman : Is it? It's worth a try. How can I apply?\nMan : Well. I'll inquire and let you know.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  남자는 프로그램에 대해 알아볼 것이다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "14. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  이 열차는 현재 멈춰 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이 열차는 서울역에서 출발했다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  이 열차는 잠시 후에 대전역에 도착한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  부산으로 가는 KTX 열차가 고장이 났다.",
            "detail"        : "Man: I'll tell you the information. Our train to Seoul is passing through the construction section now, so it is running slowly. And in order to send the KTX train to Busan first, we will stop at Daejeon Station, which is the next stop, for another 10 minutes. We apologize for the inconvenience.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  이 열차는 잠시 후에 대전역에 도착한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "15. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  오늘부터 한 달 동안 표를 반값에 판매한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  작년에도 가족을 위한 할인 티켓을 판매했다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  올해는 작년보다 일찍 야외 수영장을 이용할 수 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  티켓을 한 장 사면 티켓 한 장을 더 주는 행사를 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : The following is the life information. It's a lot of hot these days, right? The news is that the outdoor swimming pool in Han River Park will open a week earlier than last year due to the early heat. It is available at 50% of the normal price for one week after opening. Also, it is said that family tickets will be on sale from this year. It is said that 1 person can enter for free when a family visit for 4 people, so why don't you take this opportunity to go on vacation in advance?",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  올해는 작년보다 일찍 야외 수영장을 이용할 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "16. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  정오의 콘서트는 올해 처음 시작되었다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  극장을 찾는 사람들의 수가 줄어서 걱정이다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  금요일에 카페에서 커피를 마시면 콘서트 티켓을 준다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  한 달에 한 번 지휘자가 음악에 대해 설명하는 시간이 있다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I heard that the 'Noon Concert' at the Seoul Art Center is gaining a big deal of popular music.\nMan : Yes. I think it was effective to prepare various services for the audience. On the last Thursday of every month, the conductor has a ‘music story’ time to explain music to the audience. And if you watch the performance on Friday, we are offering free coffee at the cafe on the 1st floor. So the number of visitors to the 'Noon Concert' seems to have increased a lot compared to last year.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  한 달에 한 번 지휘자가 음악에 대해 설명하는 시간이 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "17. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  여행 갈 때는 새 옷을 사야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  쇼핑할 때 가격을 따져 봐야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  옷은 직접 입어 보고 사는 게 좋다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  쇼핑으로 시간을 낭비하면 안 된다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Ji-eun, what are you doing?\nWoman : Oh, I'm going on a trip next week, and I'm going to buy a dress on the Internet. You can save time and the price is cheaper than going to a department store or shopping mall in person.\nMan : It takes me a lot of time to live on the Internet. And wouldn't it be better to go and try on clothes and choose? There are many cases where the color or shape is different from what you see on the screen.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  옷은 직접 입어 보고 사는 게 좋다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "18. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  어릴 때는 여러 번 실수해도 괜찮다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  아이들이 잘못을 해도 예뻐해야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  아이들에게 심하게 말을 하면 안 된다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  아이들에게 자기 잘못을 알게 해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Why don't parents say anything even if their children do something wrong these days? I think it's a problem to be always pretty.\nWoman : It's because the children are young, but isn't it bad to say something every time?\nMan : No matter how young you are, you have to tell me what you did wrong. That way you won't make the same mistake again next time.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  아이들에게 자기 잘못을 알게 해야 한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "19. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  연휴에는 여행을 가는 것이 좋다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  기차를 타면 이동 시간을 줄일 수 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  차가 많은 연휴에는 조심해서 운전해야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  차로 가면 짐을 많이 실을 수 있어서 편하다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Ugh, there's a lot of cars because it's a holiday.\nMan: That's why I asked you to take the train. If you take the train, you'll feel more like traveling.\nWoman : But the kids have a lot of luggage and parents' presents, so isn't the car comfortable?\nMan: That's what I can do if I take it. If you make a mistake, you'll have more time in the car than when you see your parents.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  기차를 타면 이동 시간을 줄일 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "20. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  끊임없이 노력하는 자세가 중요하다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  최고가 되기 위해서는 자신을 믿어야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  성공을 위해서는 창의적인 생각이 필요하다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  식당에 오는 손님들을 첫 번째로 생각해야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : The name of the restaurant 'the second most delicious house in the world' is really interesting. Boss, is there any special reason why you named the store like this?\nMan : People these days seem to want to be number one in everything. But rather than being the best, I want to be a person who keeps moving towards the best. Because the moment I think I'm the best, I'm satisfied with it. I think there will be someone better than me, and I will always do my best in the future.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  끊임없이 노력하는 자세가 중요하다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "21. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  피자 가게의 성공은 맛에 달려 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  치킨 가게가 잘되려면 위치가 중요하다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  퇴직 후에도 할 수 있는 일을 찾아야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여러 사람의 의견을 들어야 성공할 수 있다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Honey, when you retire, shall we have a chicken shop?\nMan : It's our store....... That's good But I don't think you should think about it easily. Such a store can only be successful if it is set up in a place where a lot of people come and go, but the store is also expensive.\nWoman : A friend who goes to a pizza restaurant at the market said that if it tastes good, all the customers will come to the store no matter where it is.\nMan : Shouldn't it be a place where customers can easily find a store, though?",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  치킨 가게가 잘되려면 위치가 중요하다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "22. 들은 내용으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  남자는 회사를 퇴직했다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  남자는 시장에서 가게를 운영한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 치킨 가게를 하고 싶어 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자의 친구는 시장에서 치킨 가게를 한다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Honey, when you retire, shall we have a chicken shop?\nMan : It's our store....... That's good But I don't think you should think about it easily. Such a store can only be successful if it is set up in a place where a lot of people come and go, but the store is also expensive.\nWoman: A friend who goes to a pizza restaurant at the market said that if it tastes good, all the customers will come to the store no matter where it is.\nMan : Shouldn't it be a place where customers can easily find a store, though?",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  여자는 치킨 가게를 하고 싶어 한다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "23. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  등산로의 위치를 확인하고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  호텔까지 가는 길에 대해 묻고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  여행하려는 곳에 숙박 예약을 하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  호텔에서 진행하는 프로그램에 대해 문의하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Hello. Wooden hotel right.\nWoman : Yes, customer. How can I help you.\nMan : I made a reservation for 3 people and 1 night next Saturday. I'd like to make a reservation for a nature experience training at the hotel.\nWomen : Nature experience education is only available for groups of 20 or more.\nMan: Oh, I see. Then isn't there a family experience program that I can do with my child?\nWoman : I'm sorry, but the experience program for the family is currently being prepared. Instead, I made a bird of 'playing in the forest' where children can play on the hiking trail behind the hotel. Why don't you use this?",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  호텔에서 진행하는 프로그램에 대해 문의하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "24. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  ‘숲속놀이터’는 단체만 이용이 가능하다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  남자는 가족과 3일간 호텔에서 묵을 예정이다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  호텔에서는 가족을 위한 체험 활동을 계획 중이다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  자연 체험 교육은 최대 20명까지 수강이 가능하다.",
            "detail"        : "Man : Hello. Wooden hotel right.\nWoman : Yes, customer. How can I help you.\nMan : I made a reservation for 3 people and 1 night next Saturday. I'd like to make a reservation for a nature experience training at the hotel.\nWomen : Nature experience education is only available for groups of 20 or more.\nMan: Oh, I see. Then isn't there a family experience program that I can do with my child?\nWoman : I'm sorry, but the experience program for the family is currently being prepared. Instead, I made a bird of 'playing in the forest' where children can play on the hiking trail behind the hotel. Why don't you use this?",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  호텔에서는 가족을 위한 체험 활동을 계획 중이다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "25. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  장애인을 위한 시설을 늘려야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  장애인들에게 세금을 깎아 줘야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  정부는 운동선수의 재활을 도와야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  장애인의 자립을 위한 일자리가 필요하다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I'm talking with former national soccer player Kim Min-soo. You are running a company that employs the disabled.\nMan : Yes. As you all know, I quit playing soccer because I was disabled by a traffic accident. After becoming disabled, it was difficult to make a living. I think this is a difficulty that not only me, but all people with disabilities go through. Of course, the government provides various support to people with disabilities, such as tax benefits, but above all, I thought that people with disabilities should be able to stand on their own. That's why people who agree with me got together and set up a company that hires people with disabilities.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  장애인의 자립을 위한 일자리가 필요하다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "26. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  남자는 장애를 극복하고 국가대표가 되었다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  남자는 사고를 당해 축구를 할 수 없게 되었다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  남자는 사업가가 되기 위해 운동을 그만두었다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자는 정부 지원을 받기 위해 회사를 설립했다.",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I'm talking with former national soccer player Kim Min-soo. You are running a company that employs the disabled.\nMan : Yes. As you all know, I quit playing soccer because I was disabled by a traffic accident. After becoming disabled, it was difficult to make a living. I think this is a difficulty that not only me, but all people with disabilities go through. Of course, the government provides various support to people with disabilities, such as tax benefits, but above all, I thought that people with disabilities should be able to stand on their own. That's why people who agree with me got together and set up a company that hires people with disabilities.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  남자는 사고를 당해 축구를 할 수 없게 되었다.",
            "score"         : "2"
        }
    ]
}
